# Jonathan Toye

# Software Developer

Toronto, ON | 613-324-7846 | jontoye@gmail.com



# **PROFILE**

Highly curious full stack developer with a passion for problem solving and learning. I bring a mixed background of engineering and hospitality that combine to deliver exceptional user experiences. Effective and empathetic communication skills allow me to work productively within any team environment.

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Scrabble**

A browser-based version of Scrabble. Fully interactive user interface that accurately tracks and displays list of played words and player scores. Demonstrates knowledge of basic front-end technologies, DOM manipulation, and MVC architecture.

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, Javascript

# **Al Adventure**

An Al-based choose your own adventure game. Users interact with Al generated responses to build characters and stories. Collaborated with team members to design, implement, test, debug, and deploy within the required timeframe.

Technologies Used: MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js, OpenAl API

#### **Album Collector**

Web application where users can search for and collect their favourite albums. Data is pulled in using Spotify's Web API and is searchable by either artist name or album name. Demonstrates ability to neatly present data using RESTful API's, Full Stack Web Frameworks, and RDBMS.

Technologies Used: Django, PostgreSQL, Spotify API

# Ice Hub

Tool for managing hockey league data. Created for league administrators to assist with organizing teams, schedules, and game results. Demonstrates knowledge of server-side programming, NoSQL databases, authentication, and authorization.

Technologies Used: MongoDB, Express, Node.js

#### SKILLS AND AWARDS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Express, React, Python, Django, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, GitHub, Mocha, Jest, Gatsby, GraphQL

#### **Best Discord Bot**

GryphHacks Hackathon 2022

#### **EDUCATION**

**Software Engineering**General Assembly, Toronto 2022

**Culinary Management Diploma** Algonquin College, Ottawa 2016

**B.A.Sc. Civil Engineering** University of Ottawa, Ottawa *2012* 

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Baker**

Blackbird Baking Co, Toronto Oct 2017 - Jan 2022

# Cook

Beckta Dining & Wine, The Albion Rooms, Dish Catering, Brookstreet Hotel, Ottawa Mar 2015 - Sep 2017

#### **Project Associate**

Halsall Associates, Ottawa Feb 2013 - Nov 2014